<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HPC R</title>
    <link>/hpc-r/</link>
    <description>Recent content on HPC R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 15:57:19 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/hpc-r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>/hpc-r/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 15:57:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hpc-r/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Installation Install Hugo Hugo itself is just a single binary without dependencies on expensive runtimes like Ruby, Python or PHP and without dependencies on any databases.
Note
Currently, this theme makes use of features that will be part of the Hugo v0.16 release. You have to compile the latest developement version yourself.
 Let&amp;rsquo;s make sure Hugo is set up as expected. You should see a similar version number in your terminal:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding content</title>
      <link>/hpc-r/adding-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 20:26:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hpc-r/adding-content/</guid>
      <description>Hello world Let&amp;rsquo;s create our first content file for your documentation. Open a terminal and add the following command for each new file you want to add. Replace &amp;lt;section-name&amp;gt; with a general term that describes your document in detail.
hugo new &amp;lt;section-name&amp;gt;/filename.md  Visitors of your website will find the final document under www.example.com/&amp;lt;section-name&amp;gt;/filename/.
Since it&amp;rsquo;s possible to have multiple content files in the same section I recommend to create at least one index.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap</title>
      <link>/hpc-r/roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 20:08:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hpc-r/roadmap/</guid>
      <description>Quo vadis? The port of the original Alabaster theme has replicated nearly all of its features. A few are still missing, but I&amp;rsquo;ve good news: the Hugo community is actively working on this issues. Maybe with the next release of Hugo we can abandon this list. Stay tuned.
Planned features Localization Currently, it is possible to collect all strings in a single place for easy customization. However, this only enables you to define all strings in a single language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-performance R</title>
      <link>/hpc-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 15:21:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hpc-r/</guid>
      <description>R is not a fast language. But we can make it faster. This tutorial covers a number of techniques we can use to parallelize and speed up our code. A lot of the material is borrowed from Hadley Wickham&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Advanced R&amp;rdquo; book.
In particular, this workshop combines a review of basic R syntax (making sure everyone is up to speed) with more advanced R concepts. Topics covered include the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/hpc-r/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hpc-r/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>